# Abdelsalam Habara

Experienced Accountant transitioning to Software Engineering, with strong organisation and motivation. Customer-oriented with a focus on quality and teamwork. Passionate about utilising my specialised skill sets to assist clients and stakeholders through software, financial literacy and more.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Deloitte, Melbourne — Cyber Risk Vacationer

NOV 2022 - FEB 2022

Worked across a number of different streams including Identity, Cloud and App Security, developing strategies and plans for clients. Worked in Cloud Security (AWS, Azure) and IAM (Sailpoint, CyberArk, ForgeRock, Okta, Oracle, SAP) to provide solutions for ASX listed corporations.

### E & P Financial Group, Canberra — Junior Accountant

MAY 2018 - FEB 2021

Managed a large client portfolio in accounting and administration of SMSFs, lodging financial statements, reducing tax exposure, restructuring funds, training junior accountants, automating accounting practices, maintaining business relationships.Responsibilities included:

- Preparing, completing and lodging SMSF Annual Financial Statements and Tax Return for high net-worth clients personally managing over \$200 million in funds
- Assisted clients in the implementation of financial strategies successfully reducing tax exposure
- Ensured SMSFs are pursuant to current legislation annually including successfully restructuring funds to meet the \$1.6 million transfer balance cap
- Provided training and support to other junior Accountants and interns
- Automated accounting practices for mergers of ASX listed funds and REITs
- Maintained long-term business relationships with key clients, ATO and stakeholders

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Monash University,** Melbourne — *Master of Information Technology*

JUL 2021 - Present

**Australian National University ,** Canberra — Bachelor of Accounting/Bachelor of Arts

IAN 2016 - DEC 2019

О ма

Melbourne

**&** 0435026528

🖾 abdelsalam.habara1997@gmail.com

ahabara.github.io

រ៉ៃណិ LinkedIn

#### **SKILLS**

BGL360, Taxation Law, SMSF Regulation, FE Development

#### **AWARDS AND EXTRACURRICULARS**

DiversIT Events Officer - 2021 Led a webdev workshop for high school girls and non-binary students, emceed a panellist Q&A for post-graduate IT students with major tech companies as part of a student-led initiative promoting inclusion and diversity within the Monash IT faculty.

Scholarship Recipient - 2019
One of 20 students from around the world to attend a European
Commission-funded course on
Migration in Europe in Berlin, Germany

## Treasurer at ANU Middle Eastern Society - 2019

Worked dynamically with superiors, coordinated meetings and conferences. Worked with ambassadors, notable speakers, and politicians.

## Treasurer at ANU Gender Equity Society - 2019

Responsible for administering society accounts, negotiating funding and budgeting. Passionate about gender equality and inclusive in professional environments.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Javascript, TypeScript, React, HTML, CSS, Java, Spring, Python, SQL